

David Macpherson

Summary

I am computer science, hardware engineering, and robotics student at the Academies of Loudoun. I have 8+ years of experience in programming, and 4 years experience in Al & ML applications. Using my skills to make real change in the world is my goal.

Profiles

() ironon



Experience

5338 FRC Robotics Team

November 2023 - Present

Developer

https://github.com/roboloco-5338

I'm a software developer for the 5338 Robotics Team, one of the top teams in the Chesapeake area.

Offical School Website Creator

August 2021 - Present

Owner

Tuscarora High School

http://tuskytime.org

I am the official creator & maintainer of a website for my school that is used by thousands of students every week to help with scheduling issues.

Technology Student Association

November 2024 - Present

Member

https://tsaweb.org/

I am a member of the Technology Student Association, and I've been building an autonomous rover to compete in a state-wide competition.

Projects

AutoNote October 2023

https://ironon.me/project/?id=1

Uses AI and LLM technologies to turn a teacher's notes slideshow into studyable, actionable flashcards. Greatly improves studying efficiency.

Automatic Key Maker

December 2024

https://ironon.me/project/?id=7

LLM system that can accurately solve college-level problems from nearly every field of science and mathematics by leveraging new advances in agentic AI, and by using LLM's code generation abilities.

Weekend 3D Printed Robot

November 2023

https://ironon.me/project/?id=9

In order to guarantee my admission into my school's local robotics team, I prototyped, designed, 3d-printed, wired, and programmed a fully functional miniature robot in the span of 2 days.

Education

Academies of Loudoun 4.51 GPA

November 2023 - Present

AET Engineering

https://www.lcps.org/o/acl

I am a student at a highly-selective specialized STEM magnet school

Awards

AcademiesHacks Hardware Winner

Academies of Loudoun

March 2024

National Merit Scholarship Letter of

Commendation

CollegeBoard

November 2024

Skills

Data Science w/ Python

••••

Machine Learning / LLM Engineering

••••

Backend Development

••••

Frontend Development

••••

Robotics w/ WPILib

••••

Computational Statistics with R

••••

AWS Cloud Engineer

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$

Embedded Systems Development

• • • • 0

Languages

Python

••••

C++

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$

Rust

• • • • 0

MATLAB

•••00

ŀ